A Guide to the Staunton (Va.) City Council Records, 1819-1965
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Staunton (Va.) City Council Records, 1819-1965
The Library of Virginia
1050924, 1050926-1050929, 1050931-1050971
46 cu. ft. (46 boxes)
Staunton (Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipment from the City of Staunton.
Historical Information
The city of Staunton, in Augusta County, was named, according to tradition, for Rebecca Staunton, wife of Sir William Gooch, lieutenant governor of Virginia from 1727 to 1749. Staunton was laid out in 1748 at the site of the Augusta County courthouse and was established as a town in 1761. It was incorporated as a town in 1801 and as a city in 1871.
Scope and Content
Staunton (Va.) City Council Records 1819-1965, consists of Account Settlements, Bids, Bills, Commissioner of Safety reports, County Levies, Deliquent Lists, Election Nominations, Mayor's Reprorts, Minutes of Overseer's for the Poor, Ordinances, Petitions, Police Reports and Resolutions.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Staunton court records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Staunton (Va.) Circuit Court
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Staunton (Va.)
Geographical Names:
Staunton (Va.)--History
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Staunton (Va.)
Contents List
- Records,, 1819-1838., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050924)
  Commissioner of safety reports, delinquent lists, bills, resolutions, ordinances, election nomination [Series #s 1-18]
- Records,, 1848-1856., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050926)
  Ordinances, reports of minutes of overseers of the poor, petitions, account settlemets [Series #s 37-46]
- Records,, 1856-1859., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050927)
  Resolutions, mayor's reports, vouchers, bids, etc. [Series #s 46-49]
- Records, 1853-1863., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050928)
  Public work contracts and receipts, mayor reports police papers, etc. [Series #s 50-53]
- Records, 1839-1849., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050929)
  Bills, Reports, delinquent lists, county levies, [Series #s 19-36]
- Records, 1849-1869., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050931)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 54-59]
- Records, 1879-1880., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050932)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 69-70]
- Records, 1878-1879., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050933)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 68-69]
- Records, 1877-1879., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050934)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 67-68]
- Records, 1870-1872., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050935)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 60-62]
- Records, 1872-1876., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050936)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 62-66]
- Records, 1880-1895., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050937)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 79-85]
- Records, 1882-1884., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050938)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 72-74]
- Records, 1884-1889., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050939)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 74-78]
- Records, 1880., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050940)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #70]
- Records, 1881-1882., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050941)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 71-72]
- Records, 1896-1897., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050942)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 85-87]
- Records, 1905-1906., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050943)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 95-96]
- Records, 1903-1904., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050944)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 93-94]
- Records, 1906-1907., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050945)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 96-97]
- Records, 107-1911., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050946)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 98-101]
- Records, 1902-1903., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050947)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 92-93]
- Records, 1898-1902., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050948)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 88-92]
- Records, 1912-1913., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050949)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 102-103]
- Records, 1903-1916., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050950)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 103-106]
- Records, 1916-1917., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050951)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 106-107]
- Records, 1917-1921, 1923-1924., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050952)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 107-111, 113-114]
- Records, 1924-1925., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050953)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 114-115]
- Records, 1925., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050954)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series # 115]
- Records, 1929-1932., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050955)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 119-122]
- Records, 1935-1938., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050956)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 125-128]
- Records, 1933-1934., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050957)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 123-124]
- Records, 1932., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050958)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series # 122]
- Records, 1927-1928., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050959)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 117-118]
- Records, 1926., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050960)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series # 116]
- Records, 1938-1939., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050961)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 128-129]
- Records, 1939-1946., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050962)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 129-136]
- Records, 1946-1948., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050963)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 136-138]
- Records, 1948-1951., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050964)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 138-141]
- Records, 1951-1952., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050965)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 141-142]
- Records, 1951-1955., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050966)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 142-148]
- Records, undated., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050967)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series # 158]
- Records, 1955-1965., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050968)
  Lists of Hustings, building permits, white registrations,
- Records, 1830-1900, 1920., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050969)
- Records, 1955-1965., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050970)
  Reports, ordinances, resolutions, etc. [Series #s 145-153]
- Records, 1920-1950., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1050971)